Classes Collection UA039
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Classes, 1816 -- 2022; 1857 -- 2000; UA039.001; 32.45 Linear Feet; 2 Volumes; 10 Digital Object(s) Of the 10 digital objects in this series, 2 have extent information comprising 18 files.; 56.0 Megabytes Of the 10 digital objects in this series, 2 have extent information comprising 67.7 MB.
  - Classes of 1970-1979, 1970 -- 2014; UA039.001.013
    - Gwen Schneidkraut audio recording 1974, 2014; UA039.001.012.00029 (Box 12)
      This CD contains four mp3 files of Gwen Schneidkraut singing folk and rock songs while playing acoustic guitar. Gwen S1.mp3 and part of Gwen S2.mp3 were recorded on September 14, 1974 at MacPhie Dining Hall. The remainder of Gwen S2.mp3, as well as Gwen S3.mp3 and Gwen S4.mp3, were recorded on November 9, 1974. Though Gwen Schneidkraut is the primary performer, Leslie Cooper and Helen Cohen accompany her at different points during the recordings. All were occupational therapy students from the class of 1976. The sound quality of Gwen S1.mp3 is better than the other recordings. The CD also contains an MS Word .docx file detailing the contents of the CD, as well as an mp3 recording of a WGBH radio show from May 31, 1963, which has no connection to Tufts.
      Song Listing:
      Gwen S1.mp3 You Can Close Your Eyes Hard-Lovin' Loser Song written by Gwen Schneidkraut and her brother Ruby Tuesday These Days You Got to Hide Your Love Away Love Has No Pride I'm a Woman Summertime The Marvelous Toy
      Gwen S2.mp3 Will You Still Love Me Tomorrow Something in the Way He Moves Help Me Make It Through the Night Marcie Carolina in My Mind Looking for You and I Don't Know Where Let It Be Love Has No Pride Love Me Like a Man Urge for Going
      Gwen S3.mp3 No Regrets Reason to Believe Something's Wrong Yiddish song [title unintelligible] Kretchma Leaves That Are Green Will You Still Love Me Tomorrow Ring-Around-A-Rosy Rag There But For Fortune Pack Up Your Sorrows
      Gwen S4.mp3 I Shall Be Released I Like Mountain Music The Song Is Love You Ain't Goin' Nowhere If I Had Wings These Days Single Girl Daddy, You Been On My Mind 4+20 Your Love's Return Until It's Time for You to Go
      CD
    - Class of 1970 photographs, UA039.001.063.00009 (Box 63)
    - Life Magazine article on alternative graduations, 1970; UA039.001.072.00001 (Box 72)
      Article features Tufts class of 1970. Donated by Bill Garfield see in top photo on p. 24.
    - Jean Mayer at Alumni Day, 1979; UA039.001.DO.00125; Unknown (Box Shared 27)
      People; College presidents; Alumni Day; Mayer, Jean
  - Classes of 1980-1989, UA039.001.014
    - Classes, 1980; UA039.001.012.00008 (Box 12)
      Program, Class Day; Class of 1980 profile; 15th reunion booklet, School of Medicine; correspondence; audiotape of Class Day 1980 with Dan Rather.
    - Classes, 1981; UA039.001.012.00009 (Box 12)
      Program, Awards Dinner Dance; correspondence, 25th reunion booklet.
    - Classes, 1982; UA039.001.012.00010 (Box 12)
      Pamphlet, Senior Pledge Drive; Class of 1982 profile; publication, "Hollow Pillars: The Tufts Experience?"; 15th reuinion, School of Medicine; correspondence, 25th reunion booklet.
    - Classes, 1983; UA039.001.012.00011 (Box 12)
      Invitation, program, Awards Dinner Dance; award cards, Awards Dinner Dance; publication, "Over the Hill: A Look Back at Tufts"; 15th reunion booklet, School of Medicine; correspondence.
    - Classes, 1984; UA039.001.012.00012 (Box 12)
      Program, Awards Dinner Dance; 10th and 15th reunion booklets, School of Medicine.
    - Classes, 1985; UA039.001.012.00013 (Box 12)
      Program, Medical Alumni Weekend and Reunion Days, School of Medicine; publication, "Increased Wattage: Brightening the Light on the Hill"; 10th reunion booklet, School of Medicine.
    - Classes, 1986; UA039.001.012.00014 (Box 12)
      Program, Awards Dinner Dance; program, Medical Alumni Weekend, School of Medicine.
    - Classes, 1987; UA039.001.012.00015 (Box 12)
      Program, Senior Dinner Dance; class lists.
    - Classes, 1988; UA039.001.012.00016 (Box 12)
      10th reunion booklet, School of Medicine('88).
    - Classes, 1988; UA039.001.012.00017 (Box 12)
      5th and 10th reunion booklets, School of Medicine ('89); faculty awards list.
    - Dan Rather's "Four Years in 60 Minutes" script for 1980 Class Day, UA039.001.012.00027 (Box 12)
      Script given by Dan Rather at the 1980 Class Day accompanied with a slide show. Slides are in UA039/001-068.
    - Classes, video: Commencement, 1987; UA039.001.019.001 (Box 19)
    - Classes, video: Commencement, 1987; UA039.001.020.001 (Box 20)
    - Classes, video: Commencement, 1988; UA039.001.021.001 (Box 21)
      "Time of my Life"
    - Classes, video: Commencement, 1989; UA039.001.022.001 (Box 22)
      "Remembering the Good Times".
    - Classes, video: Commencement, 1989; UA039.001.023.001 (Box 23)
      "Remembering the Good Times", long version.
    - Class of 1985 photographs, UA039.001.063.00010 (Box 63)
      Photograph of Robert Vey, A '85.
    - Slides, Class of 1980 Class Day with Dan Rather, UA039.001.068.00001 (Box Shared 41)
    - Gordon Sterling, Class of 1985, eulogy, 2015; UA039.000503 (Box 12, Folder 30)
      Gift of Sol Gittleman, 2020, accession UA-2020-056.
  - Classes of 1990-1999, 1988 -- 1999; UA039.001.015
    - Classes, 1990; UA039.001.012.00018 (Box 12)
      Freshman directory; class book, "The Academic Year"; program, Senior Dinner Dance (90'); 5th reunion booklet, School of Medicine.
    - Classes, 1991; UA039.001.012.00019 (Box 12)
      Program, Senior Dinner Dance ('91).
    - Classes, 1992; UA039.001.012.00020 (Box 12)
      Class book, "The Academic Year"; freshman directory; profile notes for class entering 1988; 5th reunion booklet, School of Medicine; correspondence; program, Awards Banquet.
    - Classes, 1993; UA039.001.012.00021 (Box 12)
      Class book, "The Academic Year"; freshman record; program, Awards Banquet; program, Centennial Ball; 5th reunion booklet, School of medicine.
    - Classes, 1994; UA039.001.012.00022 (Box 12)
      Class book, "The Academic Year"; "Who's New on Campus"; award recipients, School of Medicine; 5th reunion booklet, School of Medicine.
    - Classes, 1995; UA039.001.012.00023 (Box 12)
      Class book, "The Academic Year".
    - Classes, 1996; UA039.001.012.00024 (Box 12)
      Freshman directory, commencement programs
    - Classes, 1997; UA039.001.012.00025 (Box 12)
      Freshman directory, Academic handbook for entering students and advisors.
    - Classes, 1998; UA039.001.012.00026 (Box 12)
      First year student record.
    - Classes, video: Baccalaureate Service May 19, 1990; UA039.001.024.001 (Box 24)
    - Classes, video: Commencement, 1990; UA039.001.025.001 (Box 25)
      "The Best of Times"
    - Classes, video: Commencement, 1990; UA039.001.026.001 (Box 26)
      "The Best of Times".
    - Classes, video: Commencement, 1990; UA039.001.027.001 (Box 27)
      "The Best of Times", short version.
    - Classes, video: Commencement, 1991; UA039.001.028.001 (Box 28)
      "Tuftonian Memories".
    - Classes, video: Commencement, 1991; UA039.001.029.001 (Box 29)
      "Tuftonian Memories", short version.
    - Classes, video: Commencement, 1992; UA039.001.030.001 (Box 30)
      "Tuftonia's Way".
    - Classes, video: Commencement, 1993; UA039.001.031.001 (Box 31)
      "Tufts in '93".
    - Classes, video: Commencement, 1993; UA039.001.032.001 (Box 32)
    - Classes, video: Commencement, 1994; UA039.001.033.001 (Box 33)
      "We are the Class of 1994".
    - Classes, video: Commencement, 1994; UA039.001.034.001 (Box 34)
      "We are the Class of 1994", short version.
    - Classes, video: Baccalaureate Service, 1995; UA039.001.035.001 (Box 35)
    - Classes, video: Commencement, 1995; UA039.001.036.001 (Box 36)
      "The Star Spangled Banner".
    - Classes, video: Commencement, 1995; UA039.001.037.001 (Box 37)
      "Tufts is Alive in 1995".
    - Classes, video: Commencement, 1996; UA039.001.038.001 (Box 38)
      "Brown and Blue Mix...Tufts '96".
    - Classes, video: Commencement, 1996; UA039.001.039.001 (Box 39)
      "Brown and Blue Mix...Tufts '96", short version.
    - Classes, video: Commencement, 1997; UA039.001.040.001 (Box 40)
    - Classes, video: Commencement, 1997; UA039.001.041.001 (Box 41)
      Tufts in Heaven in '97.
    - Classes, video: Commencement, 1997; UA039.001.042.001 (Box 42)
      Tufts in Heaven in '97, short version.
    - Classes, video: Commencement, 1998; UA039.001.043.001 (Box 43)
      "Tufts is Great in 98'".
    - Classes, video: Commencement Address, 1999; UA039.001.044.001 (Box 44)
      David Halbostrom.
    - Classes, video: Commencement, 1999; UA039.001.045.001 (Box 45)
      "Tufts is Fine in 99'".
    - Classes, video: Commencement, 1999; UA039.001.046.001 (Box 46)
    - Classes, video: Commencement, 1999; UA039.001.047.001 (Box 47)
      "Tufts is Fine in 99'", short version.
    - Classes, video: Tufts University Commencement Speakers, 1988 -- 1994; UA039.001.048.001 (Box 48)
      Gloria Steinem; Dr. Jean Mayer and Clifton Wharton; Dr. Jean Mayer and Dr. Robert Coles; Dr. Jean Mayer and Perez de Cuellar; Dr. Jean Mayer and Ted Turner; Dr. Jean Mayer and Bernard Gordon; Dr. John DiBiaggio and Carlos Fuentes; Dr. John DiBiaggio and Ted Koppel.
    - Slides, Class of 1999 Senior Week, UA039.001.067.00001 (Box Shared 41)
    - Homecoming Megaphone, 1996, UA039.001.076.00001 (Box Shared 81)
  - Classes of 2000-2009, 2000 -- 2006; UA039.001.016
    - Classes, 2000; UA039.001.012.00028 (Box 12)
      Jessica Blanco Colati's graduation tassel.
    - Classes, video: Commencement, 2000; UA039.001.049.001 (Box 49)
      "Tufts 2000; The Millenium Class".
    - Tufts Night at Pops, 2006, UA039.001.072.00002 (Box 72)
    - Tufts Commencement, 2004; UA039.001.072.00003 (Box 72)
      Commencement invitation
    - Tufts College Years, 1948-1952, 2002; UA039.001.074.00001 (Box 74)
      Class of 1952 video donated by Charles Fox 6/17/2002
      videocassette
  - Classes of 2010-2019, 2011; UA039.001.017
    - Class of 2011 glass mug, UA039.001.083.00001 (Box Shared 49)
  - Classes of 2020-2029, 2021 -- 2022; UA039.000506
    - Madie Nicpon memorial photographs, 2021 October; UA039.000507; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 16 files.; 56.0 Megabytes
      Transferred by Digital Collections & Archives staff, 2021, accession UA-2022-028.
      Photographs of an impromptu memorial for Madie Nicpon, Class of 2023, who died in October 2021. The memorial was located at the corner of College and Talbot Avenues for several months. One photograph of a grassy field shows where another memorial was located at Bello Field.
    - Cher Xiong memorial photographs, 2022 March; UA039.000513; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 2 files.; 11.7 Megabytes
      Transferred by Jared Smith, Director, FIRST Resource Center; Program Director, BLAST, in 2022; accession UA-2023-009.
      Photographs of a memorial outside of the FIRST Resource Center on the Tufts campus for Cher Xiong, Class of 2024, after their death on Sunday, March 13, 2022.
- Additional accessions, UA039.002
  - Classes materials, 1930 -- 2015; UA039-001 (Box 1)
    Contains class and class reunion memorabilia.
  - Helen Jane Sears Class of 1943 memorabilia, 1941 -- 2011; UA039-002 (Box 2)
  - Greta Fridlund Class of 1954 Sigma Kappa blazer and mugs, 1952 -- 1954; UA039-003 (Box 3)
  - Memorabilia from multiple alumni received from University Advancement, UA039-004.000001 (Box 4)
  - Tufts cardigan, unknown date, UA039-005 (Box 5)
  - Caroline Woodruff campus postcards and pennant, 1900 -- 1918; UA039-006 (Box 6)
    8 Tufts campus postcards, circa 1900-1918; 2 Jumbo cards, date unknown; Tufts pennant, date unknown
  - Clifford Berlin Donick Class of 1923 scrapbook, memorabilia, class photographs, and Tufts publications, 1920 -- 1963; UA039-007 (Box 7, Box 8, Box 9)
    Class of 1923 scrapbook; tuition and fees bills, 1919-1923; Tufts Elephas, 1921; Tufts College: A Seat of Learning in New England, circa 1921; Jumbo, 1922; The Music of Tufts College, 1922; Tufts College Bulletin (Register of Alumni and Officers), 1923; Tufts College Bulletin (Annual Catallogue), 1923-1924; selected issues of Tufts Weekly, 1923-1927; Tufts College Aumni Bulletin, February 1943; Class of 1923 photo; faculty photo, 1920-1922; "American Society of Mechanical Engineers visiting engineers of Winnipeg and Minnesota at WPG, August 25-26, 1928" group photo; 1923 Reunion Committee letters to alumni, 1963
  - Gertrude Steinberg Class of 1935 Jackson College photo, news clipping, and Class Day Dance ticket, 1934 -- 1935; UA039-008 (Box 10)
  - "Songs of Tufts College Class of 1951" performed by the Odikon Singers, UA039-009 (Box 10)
    3 LP set
  - Helen Jane Sears Class of 1943 gown, UA039-010 (Box 11)
  - Class of 1886 group photograph, UA039-011 (Box Large Map Case 3 Drawer 10)
  - Paul Lockwood Leavitt, A1924, AG1927, and Dorothy Standish Lewis, J1925, papers and memorabilia, 1920 -- 1927; UA039-012 (Box 12)
  - Barnum Burns and Campus Life, 2014-2015; UA039-004.000002; 1 Digital Object(s)